thekitchenwhisperer.net 2019-12-28

# Privacy Policy

THE KITCHEN WHISPERER (“Website”) is governed by the following Privacy Policy.

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website.

At www.thekitchenwhisperer.net, the privacy of our readers and visitors is very important. This privacy policy outlines the type of personal information that is received and collected when you visit www.thekitchenwhisperer.net. We never sell your personal information to third parties.

## Log Files

Like many Web sites, www.thekitchenwhisperer.net makes use of log files.

## What information do we collect and how is it used?

  *  **Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website:  **We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form.
  *  **Information We Collect from Others:  **We may receive information about you from other sources. For example, if you use a third-party software through the site, they may transfer information to us for fulfillment.
  *  **Automatically-Collected Information:  **We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.
  *  **Cookies:** We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

 **HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED**

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

  * To operate and maintain the Website;
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries;
  * To provide you with user support;
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website;
  * To process payment for purchases you make through the Website; or,
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

Cookies are very small text files that are stored on your computer when you visit some websites. Cookies are used by most websites to tailor content and marketing messages to better suit your needs.If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.We use third party advertisers on www.thekitchenwhisperer.net to support our site. Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. This includes, but is not limited to Amazon. These third party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.thekitchenwhisperer.net send directly to your browser.

www.thekitchenwhisperer.net has no access or control over these cookies used by third-party advertisers.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. If you would like to find out more about cookies you can visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

### Types of cookies used

  *  **Google Analytics** – We use Google Analytics to understand how the website is being used in order to improve the user experience. User data is anonymous.
  *  **Google Remarketing** — Google uses these cookies to show relevant adverts to users who have previously visited our website, as they browse other websites. You can opt-out from Google’s remarketing program, by changing your Google Ad Settings.
  *  **Device-specific data –** The following information may be collected through your device and browser:
    * your device’s IP address (collected and stored in an anonymized format)
    * device screen size
    * device type (unique device identifiers) and browser information
    * geographic location (country only)
    * preferred language used to display the webpage

## Network Advertising

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

 **Display Ads  
**We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies. No personally identifiable information is shared with the Website’s ad providers.

 **Retargeting Ads  
**From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

 **Sponsored Content Tracking Pixels  
**This Website may engage in sponsored campaigns with various influencer networks, brands, and agencies. All sponsored content is duly disclosed in accordance with the FTC’s requirements. From time to time, these sponsored campaigns utilize tracking pixels (aka web beacons), which may contain cookies to collect data regarding usage and audience. This information is collected by the sponsoring company to track the results of the campaign. No personally identifiable information collected by the Website is used in conjunction with these tracking pixels.

 **Affiliate Program Participation  
**The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

The THE KITCHEN WHISPERER is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include:

  * BlogHer
  * ShareASale
  * Google Adsense
  * Amazon
  * Monumetric

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.thekitchenwhisperer.net send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

www.thekitchenwhisperer.net uses Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using Google’s [Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads) page. Users can completely block Google Analytics tracking using [Google’s Analytics Opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

## MailPoet newsletter & emails

If you have subscribed to our newsletter or if you are a member of our website (you can log in) or if you have purchased on our website, there is a good chance you will receive emails from us. We will only send you emails which you have signed up to receive, or which pertain to the services we provided to you. To send you emails, we use the name and email address you provide us. Our site also logs the IP address you used when you signed up for the service to prevent abuse of the system. This website can send emails through the [MailPoet sending service](https://www.mailpoet.com/privacy-notice/). This service allows us to track opens and clicks on our emails. We use this information to improve the content of our newsletters. No identifiable information is otherwise tracked outside this website except for the email address.

## Data Retention

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

##  **RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

 **Opt-out**  – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at tkwadmin (at) thekitchenwhisperer (dot) net to be removed from our mailing list.

 **Access**  – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to tkwadmin (at) thekitchenwhisperer (dot) net.

 **Amend**  – You may contact us at tkwadmin (at) thekitchenwhisperer (dot) net  to amend or update your personal information.

 **Forget**  – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to tkwadmin (at) thekitchenwhisperer (dot) net.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

 **SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

 **CHILDREN’S INFORMATION**

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at tkwadmin (at) thekitchenwhisperer (dot) net and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

 **CONTACT INFORMATION**

At any time, please contact us at tkwadmin (at) thekitchenwhisperer (dot) net for questions related to this Privacy Policy.

Last updated: May 23, 2018
